（カブト）僕には　何もない。
I had nothing...
まだ…　まだ足りない。
This is still not enough...
これは…　まだ僕じゃない！
This is still not me!
だから　ずっと
付け足してきたんだ。
That's why...
I've kept adding onto myself.
欲しいのは
キミの説教じゃなく→
That's why I don't need
your lectures.
キミの能力と情報なんだよ。
I need your abilities and intel.
木ノ葉の忍であり→
Not only are you
a Leaf Shinobi,
有名な　うちはの血族であり→
you're of the famed
Uchiha bloodline.
万華鏡を開眼した
写輪眼を持ち→
You possess the Sharingan that
has awakened the Mangekyo...
多くの秘密を持って戦争を止め→
You bore many secrets
and stopped a war...
多くの術と力を持っていた。
You had many jutsu
and much power.
イタチ…　キミは　キミをキミたらしめる
多くのものを持っていた。
Itachi, you possessed many things
that made you who you are.
僕の穢土転生に
これ以上の適役はいないよ。
There is no finer Reanimation
out there of mine than you.
僕のコマは　僕の力そのものだ。
And my pawns are
part of my power!
（イタチ）買いかぶりだ。
You exaggerate...
現に俺は失敗した。
The reality is, I failed.
フン…　いや　さっきは→
No, even though I mocked
the Uchiha name in front of you earlier,
キミの前で　うちはの名をなどと
強がってはみても→
やはり　その名には羨望するよ。
I'm still quite envious
of that name.
うちはという名は
あくまで血統や所属を示す。
The Uchiha name merely
identifies one's bloodline
and clan membership.
お前が名乗ったところで
意味はない。
So it's meaningless for you
to claim it.
（カブト）僕は　何者でもなかった。
I was nobody.
（カブト）僕には　何もなかった。
I had nothing.
((あの町の子だろ？
I bet he's from that city...
この前　戦闘のあったとこだよ。
where that recent battle was!
（ノノウ）ご両親は？
Where are your parents?
心配しないで。　こう見えても→
Don't worry.
医療忍術が　少しできるの。
I may not look it, but I know
some Medical Ninjutsu.
カブト！　ってのはどうかしら？
How about... Kabuto?
雑！
適当！
Sounds simple.
That was quick.
見たまんまじゃん。
（ノノウ）考えすぎないことが→
You called it by just how he looks.
It's best not to overthink things.
(一番です))
（カブト）名をもらい
居場所が与えられるまで…。
Until I was given a name...
and a place to call home...
名乗ることに意味がない？
Claiming a name is meaningless?
いや　意味はあるのさ！
No... It does hold meaning.
（サスケ）やつを殺したら
本当にダメなのか？
Are you sure we can't kill him?
すべて　後手に回るぞ！
（イタチ）それはダメだと言ったはずだ。
We're stuck playing catch-up!
I told you no!
今は　やつが戦場を仕切っている。
耐えろ。
He controls the battlefield right now.
Be patient.
イザナミは　まだなのか？
仕掛けてくる気だぞ。
Is the Izanami still not ready?
He's about to come after us!
（イタチ）こちらも仕掛けている。
だが　もう少し時間がかかる。
I'm already on him.
It's just going to take
a little more time.
大蛇丸様は　こうも言ったよ。
Lord Orochimaru said thusly...
《カブト：左近　双魔の術！》
Sakon! Demon Twin Jutsu!
《カブト：次郎坊　土遁　土陸返し！》
Jirobo! Earth Style:
Terra Shield!
（カブト）自分が何者か知りたければ→
"If you want to know who
and what you are,
この世の　あらゆるものと情報
それらを→
"all you need to do is gather
every single thing
集めつくしさえすれば
いいってね！
"and piece of information
that exists in this world!"
《カブト：鬼童丸　蜘蛛巣開！》
Kidomaru!
Spiral Web!
この糸は　刀で切れない。
These threads can't be cut
with a blade!
（サスケ／イタチ）天照！
– Amaterasu!
《カブト：君麻呂…。
Kimimaro!
屍骨脈　早蕨の舞！》
Macabre Bone Pulse!
Bracken Dance!
後ろの奥まで
蜘蛛糸を仕掛けてやがったか。
He's laid down the spider silk
all the way to the back.
後ろは　俺がやる。
兄さんは前を。
I'll get the one behind us!
Take the front, Brother!
まだ　スサノオは使えるか？
ああ！
Can you still use the Susano'o?
Yeah.
炎遁　カグツチ！
Inferno Style! Flame Control!
（カブト）奥に逃げたか。
Running away to the back?
でも　無駄だよ。
Well, it's no use!
《多由也　魔笛夢幻音鎖》
Tayuya! Demon Flute:
Chains of Fantasia!
（イタチ）大丈夫か？　サス…。
Are you okay, Sasu—?!
幻術か！
A genjutsu, huh?
お得意のスサノオでも
音までは防げないよね　やっぱり。
Even your specialty, Susano'o,
cannot stifle sound...
I knew it...
これで動きは止めた。　あとは…。
Now you're immobilized.
All that's left is...
大蛇丸様で取り込むだけ！
to take you into me
using Lord Orochimaru!
for some reason the moon is one size larger tonight
konya no tsuki wa nazeka hitomawari ookikute
it's shining brighter than it usually does
itsumo yori akaruku terasu
I trudge along the road home with my shoulders hunched
senaka wo marumete tobotobo kaeru michi
at any time I will always have a friend
donna toki mo mikata wa iru
without saying a word, it's all right to cry
nani mo iwazu naketara ii ne
once my tears dry, it will all be over
namida ga karetara owari
I need to become stronger...
motto boku ga tsuyoku naranakya
sorrow is the first step towards independence
kanashimi wa jiritsu he no ippo
how many times do I have to get hurt to forget the pain?
nando kizutsukeba itami wo wasureru
when I bleed red, I'm reminded of life
akai chi wo nagaseba inochi wo omoidasu sa
I collapse on the road with my arms and legs spread out
michi ni taore dainoji ni
I look up at the sky and think
sora wo miagete omou
true loneliness is someone without a past
shin no kodoku to wa kako no nai mono
someone who only knows the present
ima shika shiranu mono
The Izanami Activated
Well, Sasuke...
どうだい？　サスケ君。
覚えているかい？
Do you recognize
this current form of mine?
今のこの僕の姿を。
That's...!
《あれは…》
（カブト）キミが　大蛇丸様を
殺してくれたおかげで→
Thanks to you, I was finally
able to take
Lord Orochimaru into my body
after you killed him!
ついに　大蛇丸様すら僕の中に
取り込むことができたのさ！
Yes, this is my true form...
そう　これが
今の僕の本当の姿！
Remember, I said that all the laws
and principles of Nature,
大蛇丸様の集め
研究しつくしてきた→
which Lord Orochimaru researched
and compiled for so long...
自然界の法則　原理すべてが→
are now stored and
being used inside of me.
僕の中に
蓄積されてると言ったよね？
そこに足りなかったのは
この大蛇丸様自身！
The only thing that was missing...
was Lord Orochimaru himself!
Now, I have him inside me!
今や　大蛇丸様すら
僕の中にある！
キミには　感謝しても
しきれないくらいだよ　サスケ君！
I can't thank you enough, Sasuke!
Kabuto...
カブト　お前は大蛇丸じゃない。
You are not Orochimaru.
尊敬している存在を
真似るのはいい。
It's fine to imitate someone
you respect...
But don't remake yourself
into him, to that extent.
だが　その存在に
己を同一化するな。
The majority of people start out
by mimicking someone.
人の多くは　何をするにも
まず　真似事から入るものだよ。
サスケ君が　キミの真似を
していたように。
Like how Sasuke mimicked you.
Wow, Brother!
((すげえよ　兄さん！
You nailed every target,
岩の裏の死角の的にも
ど真ん中だ！
even the one in the blind spot
behind the rock!
All right, my turn!
よ～し　俺だって！
（イタチ）サスケ。
Sasuke!
It's time to go.
そろそろ帰ろう。
新しい手裏剣術を
教えてくれるって言っただろ。
You said that you would teach me
a new shuriken jutsu.
（イタチ）明日は
ちょっと大事な任務があって→
I have an important mission tomorrow
that I must prepare for.
その準備がある。
兄さんのウソつき。
You're a liar...
Sorry, Sasuke.
許せサスケ　また今度だ。
イテッ！
– Maybe some other time.
– Ow!
兄さん見てて！
Big Brother, watch this!
Hey!
とう！
こら　ムチャしたら。
Don't be reckless...
Keep at it and become great
like your brother.
（フガク）この調子で　兄さんのように
立派にやりなさい。
父さん　俺は…。
Father... I...
I wanted you to say that
you were proud of me.
(さすが　俺の子だって
言ってほしかったんだ))
その行為は
己が成長するための過程だ！
Such behavior is merely a process
to help one mature!
Don't use it as a cloak
to deceive yourself,
お前のように　己を偽るための
衣として使うな！
like you've done!
You gain nothing when
you attach your self-value
自分自身の値打ちを
称賛に値するものに結びつけ→
to something external that's admirable
and praiseworthy to you.
自分の存在意義を
見いだそうとしても→
そこには何もない。
I'll say this one last time.
最後に　もう一度言う。
Don't mislead yourself with lies.
ウソをついて　己をごまかすな。
Those who cannot acknowledge
themselves will invariably fail.
己自身を認めてやることが
できないやつは　失敗する。
（カブト）今の…　僕が失敗する？
Fail? The way I am now?
どうやって！？
How?!
Sasuke... Look into my eyes!
サスケ　俺の眼を見ろ。
そういうことか。
I understand!
Genjutsu... Sharingan!
幻術　写輪眼！
月読！
Tsukuyomi!
（イタチ）これより　イザナミに入る。
I shall now engage the Izanami.
You have already... failed.
お前はもう　失敗したんだ。
終わったのか？
Is it over?
すべてを持ってた天才には
わかりようがないよ。
A genius that had everything
would never understand...
I just want to be who
and what I am!
僕は　僕を僕にしたいだけさ。
誰にも邪魔させない！
I won't let anyone stop me.
Sa... suke...
サ…　スケ…。
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
《火遁　豪火球の術！》
Water Style: Giant Waterfall!
《水遁　大瀑布の術！》
The same moves.
（カブト）同じことを…。
さすがに手の内が読めるよ。
As expected...
It makes it easy for me to counter.
I already told you that as long as
I have my power of recovery,
言ったはずだよ。
この体の回復力があるかぎり→
wounding me is meaningless.
手傷を負わせても無意味。
Since I shut off my vision,
genjutsu won't work on me.
視界を断った僕には
幻術は一切効かない。
You have no chance of winning.
キミらに勝ち目はない。
Your fate is already in my hands.
お前の運命は
すでに俺に握られた。
Thanks to the Uchiha's other
Forbidden Jutsu.
それをなす　うちはの
もう一つの禁術　それが…。
That is...
Well then...
なら　その運命　確かめてみたいね。
Shall we put that to the test?!
イザナミだ！
... the Izanami!
Sasuke, do not leave my side.
サスケ　俺から離れるな。
Why this is just like déjà vu.
まるで　デジャヴだね。
I'm bored...
もう飽きた。
Let's end this fight already.
さっさと
この戦いを終わらせよう。
（イタチ）お前の運命を
握っているのは　俺だ。
Your fate may be in my hands now...
but you're the only one
who can truly decide
だが　お前の運命を決めるのは
お前自身だ。
how that fate shapes your destiny.
Remember what I've told you.
俺が言ったことを思い出せ。
そして　考えろ。
And think hard.
何を言ってるか
まるで　わからないね。
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
Enough of your word games.
言葉遊びは　もういい。
I will have everything...
I am the strongest of all!
すべてを手に入れる僕こそ
本当の強者！
That is fact!
それだけは　はっきりわかるよ！
己を許し　本当の自分を認める者。
He who forgives oneself,
who can acknowledge one's true self...
is the most powerful of all!
それこそが　本当の強者だ！
負け犬が…　ほざくな！！
Losers...
should be quiet!
《くっ…　これは…》
This is...
What's... going on?
《これは　どういうことだ？》
《なぜだ…　もうすでに
角は切られていたはず。
Why? That horn's already
been cut off!
How? I have no sight...
どうやって…　視界は断っていた。
I should be invulnerable to genjutsu.
どんな幻術にも
かかりようはない。
But this is clearly a...!
しかし　これは…》
What did you do to me?!
僕に何をした。
You're in my Visual Jutsu.
（イタチ）お前は俺の瞳術に　はまった。
Impossible!
ありえない！
It's the Izanami!
イザナミだ！
How...?
《どうやって…》
No matter.
いや　そんなことはどうでもいい。
No one can stop me!
この僕がやられるはずはない。
There's nothing I can't do!
僕に　できないことはない！
I told you...
言ったはずだ。
I hold your fate in my hands.
お前の運命は
俺が握っていると。
Itachi Uchiha!
うちはイタチ～！！
If this is a genjutsu...
《これが幻術というのならば》
Release!
解！
う～っ！
Calm down...
《落ち着け…　うちはの幻術。
This is an Uchiha Genjutsu.
Moreover, Itachi cast it,
so it won't be easy to undo.
それも　イタチのかけた術ならば→
簡単に破れるはずもない。
But there are many ways
to undo a genjutsu!
幻術破りなら他にも
方法はいくらでもある》
It's useless.
無駄だ。
俺の言ったことを思い返すんだ。
Recall my words to you.
Sure! I'll copy the same trick
you two used!
ああ。　あんたたちの使った手を
真似させてもらうよ！
Tayuya! Demon Flute:
Chains of Fantasia!
多由也　夢幻音鎖！
This will switch from Itachi's control
over genjutsu
《これで　イタチの幻術支配から→
to Tayuya's control.
多由也の幻術支配へと
移行すれば…》
う　うわっ！
Then, I'll do this!
ならば　こうだ！
Sage Art... Inorganic Animation!
仙法　無機転生！
This area is under my control!
この空間は　僕の支配下にある！
I'll retreat for now...
ここは　いったん退いて。
Damn it!
クッソ！　ふざけるな！
Don't mess with me!
He cannot escape
this samsara, this loop.
やつは　この輪廻…。
このループから
逃れることはできない。
This is the other Forbidden Jutsu...
the companion to Izanagi.
これが…　イザナギと対になる
もうひとつの禁術…。
運命を決める術…。
The jutsu that decides one's fate...
This is the Izanami.
これが　イザナミだ。
♪♪（太鼓）
Tailed Beast Counting Song!
All right, here we go!
（ナルト）『尾獣数え唄』
はじまり　はじまり！
One, "sleep is better than humans,"
says Shukaku
♪♪「一つ　人より
居眠り守鶴」
Two, burning in fire, Matatabi
♪♪「二つ　ファイヤー
燃えてる又旅」
Three, leave the water to Isobu
♪♪「三つ　水なら
任せろ磯撫」
Four, hot as lava, Son Goku
♪♪「四つ　溶岩
あついぜ孫悟空」
Five, always on the run, Kokuo
♪♪「五つ　いつでも
駆け足　穆王」
Six, taking it easy and
not in a hurry, Saiken
♪♪「六つ　無理せず」
Seven, the flying leaf insect,
Chomei
♪♪「アワてず犀犬」
♪♪「七つ　ナナフシ　空飛ぶ重明」
Eight, "Yeah!" is all it needs,
Gyuki
♪♪「八つ　やっぱり」
Nine, "ko-kon" cries
the mighty Kurama
♪♪「ウィーだぜ　牛鬼」
♪♪「九つ　ココンと
最強　九喇嘛」
All the Tailed Beasts have
finally come together
♪♪「とうとうそろった　尾獣の仲間」
They're a little hard,
but they're nice names
♪♪「ちょい　ムズだけどいい名前」
They're all splendid names
♪♪「みんな　立派な名前だね」
They're all wonderful names
♪♪「みんな　すてきな名前だね」
Next up, the Jinchuriki!
Here we go!
お次は　人柱力！
いくってばよ！
One, with terrible bags
under his eyes, Gaara
♪♪「一つ　ひどい
クマだよ我愛羅」
Two, with a silky voice
like a cat, Yugito
♪♪「二つ　フニャ～ンと　猫なでユギト」
Three, the Fourth Mizukage,
Yagura
♪♪「三つ　水影
四代目のやぐら」
Four, together for forty years,
Four Tails and Roshi
♪♪「四つ　４０年　四尾と老紫」
Five, tough and
powerful, Han
♪♪「五つ　いかついパワーのハン」
Six, reserved and dressed
in a kimono, Utakata
♪♪「六つ　無口な
着流しウタカタ」
Seven, the heart-warming
kunoichi, Fuu
♪♪「七つ　なごむッス　くのいちフウ」
Eight, he's got crazy rap skills,
Killer Bee
♪♪「八つ　やばいよ
ラップのキラービー」
Nine, the Leaf's
Naruto Uzumaki
♪♪「九つ　木ノ葉の
うずまきナルト」
All the powerful Jinchuriki
have finally come together
♪♪「とっても強い　人柱力のみんな」
Can they become friends
with the Tailed Beasts?
♪♪「尾獣と仲良くなれるかな？」
They're all splendid shinobi
♪♪「みんな　立派な忍だね」
They're all wonderful shinobi
♪♪「みんな　すてきな忍だね」
gozen reiji akari kieta machi
At midnight, in a city where the lights are out
koyoi wa odore tipsy night
I'm going to dance tonight Tipsy Night
tsukiakari mo todokanu basho ni wa
In a place where the moonlight doesn't reach
kodoku sae mo utau machi ga aru
There's a city that brings loneliness
kuruisou na furuesou na itami dake ga
There's only a maddening pain that makes me tremble
kowaresou na nakushisou na houseki da
It's like a fragile gemstone that could be easily lost
kuraberareru koto nado ubawareru koto nado nai
There's nothing to compare it to and it can't be stolen
kimi wa kimi de ii, saa waratte misete
You should just be yourself, Now show me a smile
nani mo kangaezutomo soko ni riyuu ga nakutomo
Even you don't think, Even if there is no reason
sore koso ga subarashii hajimari
This is a wonderful beginning
saa, yoake da
Now, dawn is about to break
gozen reiji akari kieta machi
At midnight, in a city where the lights are out
furikaereba sasou black night town
I look back and it beckons me Black Night Town
So Kabuto's trapped in
your loop now?
The Izanami is a jutsu meant
for stopping the Izanagi.
There's an escape route built
into the loop.
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
What does that mean?
美空ひばりです。
What I'm going to tell you now is
a part of the Uchiha's history,
of how the companion to the Izanagi,
the Izanami came to be.
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Izanagi and Izanami"
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
The Uchiha Clan, and
their history of conflict.
今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手
１０組の皆さんによる→